

Profile

A solution-oriented software engineer with initiative and experience managing small and large teams as a skilled and dedicated leader. With a thirst for knowledge and a determination to bring new ideas to life that will benefit others.

Experience

Research Assistant, INESC Technology and Science - Associate Laboratory

MARCH 2022 - NOVEMBER 2022

 Analyzed existing solutions to the problem of scientific data management and, as a result, adapted and applied a new solution to a specific study, the SAIL Project, an initiative that addresses climatic change.

Frontend Developer, Poweb

APRIL 2022 - SEPTEMBER 2022

• Developed and maintained the digital marketing company's website.

Vice President of Fiscal Council, Centro de Estudantes de Engenharia Informática da Universidade do Minho (CESIUM)

OCTOBER 2018 - SEPTEMBER 2019

 Cultivated CESIUM's connection with new entities in the academic community.

Education

MSc in Computer and Software Engineering, Universidade do Minho

SEPTEMBER 2017 - DECEMBER 2022

- Specialized in Distributed Systems and Parallel and Distributed Computing.
- Dissertation: Scientific Data Management.

Volunteering

Volunteer at Acolmax, Braga

JUNE 2015 - PRESENT

 Contributed to the provision of annual summer vacations for deprived children in Portugal (in places such as Costa da Caparica, Póvoa de Varzim, Castelo de Neiva, or Vila Praia de Âncora).

Mentor at Grupo de Jovens Alvorada, Braga

OCTOBER 2019 - SEPTEMBER 2022

 Mentored 15-16 years old in weekly discussions about the world, with the goal of creating a space for them to argue and, more importantly, to stimulate their thinking.

Details

Rua Quinta de Cabanas, nº74 Braga, 4700-003 914304402 rui.nbc.oliveira@gmail.com

Portfolio

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ruinbcoliveira/

https://priest110.github.io/

https://github.com/priest110

Skills

Technical (Proficient): Java, Python, C/C++, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Node.js, React.js, Vue.js, SQL, NoSQL, Docker, Git, Bash, Linux

Technical (Familiar): C#, Haskell, PHP, Erlang, Prolog

Soft: Leadership and Teamwork, Self-management, Good Communication, Critical Thinking, Creativity

Hobbies

Sports (particularly football and chess)
Puzzles and lego
Music festivals
Reading classic novels
Gardening (especially Bonsai)

Languages

Portuguese

English

Spanish

Extracurricular

Member of Green Lab Department, Society Loving the Planet Minho

JANUARY 2023 - PRESENT

 Mobilized second-hand fairs with the municipality of Braga, a pioneering movement in the city.

Director of Strategy & Sustainable Development Department, Society Loving the Planet Minho

JANUARY 2022 - DECEMBER 2022

• Initiated a program with the Sé elementary school, whose main goal was to provide children with sustainability and ecology sessions on thematic days.

Member of Strategy & Sustainable Development Department, Society Loving the Planet Minho

MAY 2020 - DECEMBER 2021

• Created and maintained internal university partners such as student centers, nuclei, and junior enterprises.

Vice President, Grupo de Jovens Alvorada, Braga

OCTOBER 2017 - SEPTEMBER 2018

• Guided the activities of the association, which had more than 40 members.

Board Member, Grupo de Jovens Alvorada, Braga

OCTOBER 2015 - SEPTEMBER 2017

• Boosted community service events in conjunction with organizations like the "Banco Alimentar".

Courses

UEFA C Coach, Associação de Futebol de Braga

DECEMBER 2022 - PRESENT

Lifeguard, Delfins ENSP

MARCH 2019 - MAY 2019